A personal knowledge base fails when unverified claims quietly become facts.
Fact Atlas adapts to desktop and mobile, connecting active exploration and daily discovery in three tabs.
Relay accepts text, a public link, or a screenshot for deep verification.
Signals routes global news by topic and date, one swipeable card at a time.
Gonka ranks importance and keeps a receipt; importance is never presented as truth.
A selected signal then enters FactRelay evidence retrieval and cross-checking.
Every source keeps its publisher, date, URL, stance, and reliability.
Truth Score is calculated by deterministic code, not generated by a model.
Invalid source indexes are rejected, and model disagreement stays visible.
The FactRelay supervisor coordinates six bounded subagents and reusable Skills.
Kimi-K2.6 forms the first evidence-based investigation.
MiniMax-M2.7 challenges circular reporting, chronology, and missing context.
Every inference preserves its upstream Gonka Request ID and order.
All inference uses GonkaRouter; a receipt proves provenance, not truth.
The user decides what enters the Atlas and confirms the place candidate.
A dark Mapbox globe makes bright fact nodes and explainable links visible.
Knowledge without a reliable place remains unplaced; coordinates are never invented.
The evidence snapshot stays browser-local as a private knowledge lineage.
Fact Atlas. Build a knowledge world. Every fact keeps receipts.