AI fact checking should not replace one black box with another.
FactRelay turns each investigation into a navigable evidence chain.
Submit text, a public link, or a social-media screenshot.
A live run extracts the claim, then retrieves current public evidence.
We test the familiar claim that the Great Wall is visible from the Moon.
FactRelay collects evidence before calling two Gonka models in sequence.
The verdict is Refuted, with a Truth Score of 9.
The score is deterministic: model consensus plus source-weighted evidence.
Every source keeps its publisher, date, URL, stance, and reliability.
Models may cite only this numbered ledger; invalid source indexes are rejected.
Kimi-K2.6 investigates and forms the first evidence-based judgment.
MiniMax-M2.7 challenges it for source laundering, chronology errors, and missing context.
Every inference preserves its upstream Gonka Request ID and execution order.
A receipt proves which call produced the analysis—not whether the claim is true.
All semantic inference runs exclusively through GonkaRouter.
Tested scoring, SSRF guards, and null preview receipts make the boundary explicit.
Verdict, Sources, Review, and Proof remain individually inspectable.
The user receives a reviewable chain—not just an answer.
FactRelay. Question the claim. Keep the receipts.